ABOUT ME

I'm a software engineer with over two years of experience in building web applications with technologies including TypeScript, Node.js, GraphQL, React, and LangChain. Previously in medicine, I found myself frequently combining domain knowledge with programming skills to build tools for myself and others, and so I switched careers to software development to focus on building my skills. I believe in taking the time to learn something well and apply it to any given task.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer (contract)

2024 - Present

LA Film Lab and Studio, Los Angeles CA

Responsible for building a component-driven architecture using TypeScript, Nuxt.js, and Node.js with Supabase, delivering mission-critical features that improved operational efficiency and customer engagement

- Developed API endpoints that retrieves and updates order information between Square's ecommerce SDK and Supabase database, processing batch transactions with error handling and real-time status tracking for customer orders
- Implemented real-time event architecture with SSE, enabling instant order updates across all platforms
- Developed an optimized kiosk system that reduced in-person order times by 25% and reduced manual errors
- Created database migration tools with Javascript and SQL, leading to successful database migration

Web Developer (contract)

2022 - 2024

Greater Boston Snow Removal, Boston MA (Hybrid Remote)

Developed business services platform that transformed company into Boston's market leader, growing from 4 to 80+ employees through coordinated dispatch and real-time communications

- Implemented microservices architecture using TypeScript and Node.js, achieving 99.9% uptime during peak snow events with 1,000+ daily transactions
- Built location-based worker matching system using Google Cloud API and MongoDB geospatial indexing reducing dispatch time by 75% and increasing worker efficiency by 40%

Clinical User Specialist Intern

2014 - 2015

Vecna Healthcare, Burlington MA

- \bullet Contributed UI/UX improvements to EMR frontend that reduced clinical documentation time by 30%
- Reduced system deployment time by 60% through automation with Ansible, managing configuration and updates across 20+ Ubuntu/Debian clinical workstations

Research Assistant in Vaccine Immunology

2011 - 2013

Vaccine Immunotherapy Center, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston MA

Performed cutting-edge transplant immunology research that increased survival through novel application of chemokine CXCL12, resulting in published findings in the prestigious American Journal of Transplantation

- Programmed 'Cellbot', an automated cell counting program in Java and ImageJ, improving efficiency and accuracy of data collection Publication:
- Alginate encapsulant incorporating CXCL12 supports long term allo and xenoislet transplantation without systemic immune suppression. *American Journal of Transplantation*, 2015. <u>DOI 10.1111/ajt.13049</u>

Jonathan Young

Web Developer rooted in domain driven design, resilience, and problem solving skills.

✓ jyoungo696@gmail.com

iterating.github.io

ngithub.com/iterating

US citizen

EDUCATION

Per Scholas

Software Engineering Track, GPA: 4.0

Completed intensive training in enterprise software development practices and Agile methodologies, achieving top performance (4.0 GPA)

University Of Massachusetts Chan Medical School

M.D. Candidate

2015 - 2018

Won American College of Physicians National Abstract Competition Publications/Conference Presentations:

- Pretending to Be the Great Pretender. *ACP Impact*, October 2016.
- A Chemokine Protective Shield for Islet Transplantation.
 Digestive Disease Interventions, Boston,

Tufts University

B.Sc. GPA: 3.7

Graduated Magna Cum Laude with Thesis Honors

 Published research in Organic and Biomolecular Chemistry on glycosidation automation



Clinical Decision Support Tools

A collection of medical calculators and decision support tools:

- Built with JavaScript and React with composition based frontend and microservice based backend architecture.
- Implemented evidence-based algorithms for clinical decision making
- · Created intuitive user interfaces for healthcare providers
- HR7 and FHIR data integration for data interoperability with medical record systems

Query Builder

Built platform that enables data analysts and developers to execute custom queries and build analytics tools

- Supports PostGreSQL, MySQL, and MongoDB databases
- · Created data visualizer for query results
- Reusable and customizable templates for time analysis, table statistics, and data quality queries

Tableau Cleaner

Modern web application designed to clean and process Tableau data files efficiently

Automated data extraction, cleaning, and transformation for use in ETL pipelines

Placenotes

Location-based social platform leveraging geofencing and real-time notifications, enabling contextual note-taking and message delivery based on users' physical locations

- Full-stack React/Node.js application with GraphQL subscriptions, Express.js, and MongoDB
- Implemented high-performance data architecture with geospatial indexing and real-time updates using MongoDB, REST, and GraphQL
- · Built advanced search functionality with text and location-based querying
- Secure JWT authentication with protected routes
- · Responsive, mobile-first UI with modern design principles



Typescript/Javascript

Python, Flask, Numpy, Scipy

GraphQL, RESTful web services

SQL, MongoDB, Firebase/Supabase

React, Nuxt, Vue

AWS, EC2, DynamoDB, ElasticBeanstalk

Git, Linux environments, Bash

Red Hat (Linux) Certified System Administrator (RHCSA)



Managed IT
 infrastructure as
 Computer Lab
 Administrator at Eliot Pearson Children's
 School, later earning Red
 Hat Certified System
 Administrator (RHCSA)
 certification

Choate Rosemary Hall

American Invitational Mathematics Examination (AIME) Qualifier

> Recognized for exceptional analytical skills and mathematical modeling, achieving top 5% performance in algorithmic challenges



